Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the International Brotherhood of Teamsters PE.018
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the International Brotherhood of Teamsters
1897-2003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
PE.018
2 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons.
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the International Brotherhood of Teamsters is an artificial collection collected and assembled by the Tamiment Library over the course of several decades. It consists of contracts, agreements, and by-laws as well as printed ephemera such as fliers, brochures, leaflets, newspaper clippings, pamphlets and other publications.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains materials from the International Brotherhood of Teamsters (IBT), International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Stablemen and Helpers of America, and the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers of America (IBTCW&H). Locals may appear under both IBT and IBTCW&H.
The files consist of agreements, constitutions, fliers and publications put out by locals as well as the union at large. Two sets of rosters, one for IBT and one for IBTCW&H are included. Most of the materials date from the 1950s-1980s. Several locals are represented, often by fliers or constitutions and agreements. Teamsters for a Democratic Union are represented in two files and were an important impetus to rid the Teamsters of corrupt practices.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into three series. Files are arranged alphabetically.
Series
International Brotherhood of Teamsters
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Stablemen and Helpers of America
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers of America
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Teamsters for a Democratic Union, New York - New Jersey Chapter Records, WAG 136
Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 282, FORE (Fear of Reprisal Ends) Records, WAG 107
Custodial History
The Tamiment Library, New York University, a special collection documenting the history of United States radicalism, labor, and progressive social action, accumulated this artificial collection of printed ephemera gradually over the years through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, organizations, and bookstores, and through exchanges with other special library collections and by ongoing collecting by staff.
Historical Note
The International Brotherhood of Teamsters (IBT) was formed in 1903 by the merger of several regional locals of teamsters, individuals who drove teams of animals, such as oxen or horses, and wagons. The union today represents a diverse membership of blue-collar and professional workers in both the public and private sectors as is evident by the various locals included in the collection, such as Ice Cream Drivers and Employees, Local 757 and Armored Car Chauffeurs and Guards, Local 820. Currently known by the name International Brotherhood of Teamsters, IBT was also briefly known as the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Stablemen and Helpers of America and later and more popularly, as the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers of America. The collection consists mainly of materials from the latter.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library. There is no accession record associated with this collection.
Clippings (information artifacts); Fliers (printed matter); Constitutions.; Pamphlets.; Labor unions -- Corrupt practices -- United States; Labor unions -- United States.; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America; Teamsters for a Democratic Union; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Stablemen, and Helpers of America; International Brotherhood of Teamsters
- Series I. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1897-2003; 260727
  - By-Laws: Proposed Model, 1978; 260677 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Circular Letters, 1958-1972, undated; 260678 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Constitution, 1991; 260679 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Eastern Conference, 1960, 1970; 260680 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Joint Council 32: Minneapolis Teamsters, 1940; 285344 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Local 1, 1959; 260681 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Local 46, 1965; 260682 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Local 96, circa 1996; 260683 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Local 111: Agreements, 1972-1985; 260684 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Local 237 (New York, NY), 1952-2003; 260690 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Local 550 (Bakery Drivers and Bakery Goods Vending Machines), undated; 270537 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Local 757 (Ice Cream Drivers and Employees), 1946; 260691 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Local 804: United Parcel Service and Strike, 1976-1997; 260692 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Local 808, undated; 372500 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Local 832, 1956, undated; 260693 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - National Black Caucus: New York Chapter, 2000; 260722 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Pamphlets and Publications, 1954, 1977, undated; 260694 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Roster, 1991-1994, 2000; 260723 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Rules: International Union Delegate and Officer Election, 1995-1996; 260724 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Teamsters Protective Benefit Association, Poughkeepsie, NY, 1897; 260725 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Western Conference Pension Plan, 1987; 260726 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Series II. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Stablemen and Helpers of America, 1938-1940; 260728
  - International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Stablemen and Helpers of America, 1938-1940, undated; 260729 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Series III. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers of America, 1952-2003; 260731
  - Agreements: National Master Freight Agreement, 1982-1988; 260738 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Agreements: National Master Freight Agreement, 1988-1991; 260739 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Agreements: National Master Freight Agreement, 1991-1998; 260740 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Agreements: Various, 1948-1986; 260741 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Central Conference of Teamsters, 1955-1961, undated; 260742 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Communications Division, 1963; 260743 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Conference: Women in the Workplace, 1986; 260744 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Constitution, 1947-1966; 260745 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Constitution, 1971-1976; 260746 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Constitution, 1981, 1986; 260747 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Constitution: Various Locals, 1963-1971, undated; 260748 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Convention, 1976; 260749 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Department of Legislation and Political Education, 1977; 260750 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - DRIVE (Democratic, Republican and Independent Voter Education); includes photos, 1971, undated; 260751 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Headquarters Building Dedication, 1955; 260752 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Joint Council 16, 1963-1964, undated; 260753 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Local 46, undated; 260754 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Local 52 (Bakery, Tea, Coffee and Yeast Drivers), 1932; 270538 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Local 85, 1979; 260755 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Local 107 (Highway Truck Drivers and Helpers), undated; 260756 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Local 111 (Communications Trade Division), 1980-1984; 260757 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Local 111: MCI Strike, 1983-1984, undated; 260758 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Local 115, undated; 326075 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Local 138, 1991, undated; 260759 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Local 194 (Bakery Drivers and Salesmen), 1981; 270527 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Local 237 (New York, N.Y.), 1973-1974, undated; 260760 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Local 239, 1962; 260761 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Local 249, 1991; 260762 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Local 282 (Building Material Industry), 1990; 260763 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Local 296, 1979; 260764 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Local 525 (Alton, IL), 1965; 260765 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Local 602 (Milk Wagon Drivers and Dairy Employees), 1947, undated; 260766 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Local 641 (Jersey City, NJ), undated; 260767 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Local 676, undated; 260768 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Local 677, 1960, 1984; 260769 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Local 688 (St. Louis, MO), 1954, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Local 707 Highway Motor Freight, 2000; 325515 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Local 802 (Bakery Drivers Union), 1966; 270539 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Local 807, 1952-1954, 1979; 260892 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Local 810, 1970, 1976, 1994, undated; 260893 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Local 812 (Soft Drink Workers), 1965; 260894 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Local 814: Agreements, 1974, 1983; 260895 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Local 817, undated; 260896 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Local 820 (Armored Car Chauffeurs and Guards), undated; 260897 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Local 840, 1972, 1995; 260898 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Local 912, undated; 260899 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Local 917, undated; 260900 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Local 1518, 1972, undated; 260901 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1960-1987; 260902 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Pamphlets and Publications, 1957, 1973; 260903 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Pamphlets and Publications, 1977-1984; 260910 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Pension Plan: Central States, Southeast and Southwest Areas, 1967; 260904 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Rank and File, 1972-2001, undated; 260911 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Rank and File: Legal Rights Handbook; published by Education and Legal Defense Foundations, 1978, 1984; 260912 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Roster I, 1969, 1978-1991; 260905 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Roster II, 1969, 1978-1991; 260906 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Stewards Manuals, undated; 260908 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Taxis, 1968; 260909 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Teamsters for a Democratic Contract, 1976; 372501 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Teamsters for a Democratic Union (TDU) I, 1976-2002, undated; 260913 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Teamsters for a Democratic Union (TDU) II, 1976-2002, undated; 260914 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Teamsters for a Democratic Union (TDU) III, 1976-2002, undated; 326076 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Teamsters for a Democratic Union (TDU) IV, 1976-2002, undated; 326077 (Box 2, Folder 48)